

Cardiff University
Cardiff Wales UK
CF24 4AG
(+44) 7871893195
HuangX50@cardiff.ac.uk

### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a PhD student in the School of Computer Science & Informatics at Cardiff University, focusing on Human-centred Computing: **Virtual Reality Exergaming Based Therapy**.

I am interested in XR (Mixed Reality, Virtual Reality and Augmented Reality), affective computing, psychological treatments, immersive media technologies, cultural heritage and game development. And also, be open to exploring all potential possibilities for human-computer interaction.

Before September of 2023, I achieved my MSc in Human-Computer Interaction at The University of Nottingham and my B.E. in Landscape Architecture at Beijing Forestry University, with work experience as a landscape architect in China and an information support assistant of the Clifford Whitworth library at University of Salford.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Master of Science in Human-Computer Interaction**

SEP 2021-SEP 2022

University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK

**Modules Include:** Programming, Mixed Reality, Human-Computer Systems, Advanced Methods in Human Factors & Human-Computer Interaction, Design Ethnography, Simulation & Optimisation for Decision Support, Studying Human Performance

Overall GPA (Without Dissertation): Merit

**Dissertation:** Investigation into the Potential for Augmented Reality Storytelling Based on the Usage of Artcodes Technology During a Museum Visit

**Award:** The best Python Game project in COMP4008(Programming)

#### **Bachelor of Engineering in Landscape Architecture**

SEP 2014-JUN 2018

Beijing Forestry University, Beijing, China

**Modules Include:** Advanced Mathematics, Engineering Mechanics, Fundamentals of Computer Application, Landscape Architecture DESIGN, Architectural Structure and Construction, Architectural Design of landscape architecture, Computer Aided Landscape Architecture Design, Urban green space System planning, etc

**Overall GPA:** 82.6/100.0

**Dissertation:** Landscape Planning & Design of Riverfront Public Areas and Transformation of Interactive Spaces of Baiquan River

#### **OxML Machine Learning Summer School**

JUN 2022-AUG 2022

University of Oxford's St Catherine's College, Online, UK

- Visited some of the latest projects, such as Huawei's River Map.
- Grasped the fundamentals of machine learning and its applications in finance.

### **Code First Girls Online Courses**

MAR 2023-MAY 2023

- UK: Introduction to JavaScript
- UK Introduction to Web Development
- Redkite Introduction to Data & SQL

#### Coursera Google UX Design Certification

JAN 2022-MAY 2022

• Commanded the UX design methods like wireframing, prototyping, Figma, AdobeXD, and the like. Gained specific knowledge of UX principles, such as de-biasing, inclusive design, design psychology, user interviews, etc.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

## Information Support Assistant

MAR 2023-JULY 2023

Clifford Whitworth Library, The University of Salford, Manchester, UK

- Worked with library staff to maintain a high-quality environment that met customer learning needs
- Provided accurate and accessible answers to customer inquiries through various communication channels
- Supported and troubleshooted library equipment to ensure smooth operation of library spaces.

## Quiet Mornings Volunteer (Part time)

FEB 2023-NOW

The Whitworth Gallery, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK

- Helped lead open sessions for families with additional needs, using sensory items to facilitate multi-sensory play
- Created an inclusive and enjoyable experience and offering support to ensure positive outcomes for all participants

### Sales Assistant (Part time)

SEP 2022-JAN 2023

Ambilight Electric LTD, Bolton, UK

- Took and edited photos and videos to advertise the products.
- Developed and maintained a website built on the WIX platform.
- Responsible for an array of platforms, including Amazon, ETSY, and Wayfair.
- Took charge of customer service, answering inquiries and dealing with lost and misplaced orders with a focus on good service and customer retention.

## Creative Career of Nottingham Advantage Award (Part time)

NOV 2021- MAR 2022

Nottingham Lakeside Arts, Nottingham, UK

# Research Secretary Assistant

MAR 2020-SEP 2020

Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China

## Assistant Landscape Architect Designer

Aoya Landscape Planning and Design Co., LTD, Zhejiang & Beijing, China

JUN 2019-MAR 2020

NOV 2018-MAY 2019

# Assistant Landscape Architect Designer

ANG Landscape Consulting Company, Beijing, China

# **SKILLS AND INTERESTS**

- Coding Skill: Python, C#, JavaScript
- UX Skills: WIX, Figma, User Research, Questionnaire Design
- Software Skills: Unity, AnyLogic, SketchUp, Lumion, SPSS, ArcGIS, Adobe Creative, MS Office, OneDrive
- Language Skills: English (Proficient-IELTS 6.5); Chinese (Native)